ALI ZAHID

MY GITHUB REPOSITORIES

https://github.com/AliZahid117?tab=repositories

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am passionate about software development, and I am currently self-learning online from Codeacademy's full-stack engineering course. I have been building various projects in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, which I have linked on this CV to my GitHub repositories, and my website is linked on this CV. I wish to take my learning to the next level through your Skills Bootcamps in Software Development. I will be a great candidate because I am enthusiastic and passionate about learning software development. From making my first computer at the age of eight to now learning how to code I have always been fascinated by computers. I have proven skills in project management from seven years managing a property business, I also have international experience working in America and Belgium.

WORK HISTORY

Manager, 08/2017 – 02/2024 Z Properties, London

- Seven years managing a family property portfolio of five houses.
- Responsibilities as manager included: preparing the yearly tax return, hiring, and managing builders for repairs and refurbishments on the houses, acquiring new and maintaining existing tenants, and dealing with tenant queries.
- I built positive relationships with my tenants to maintain the high standards of the company brand.
- Identified, planned, and implemented new real estate projects.
- Carried out refurbishments on the houses to increase profits by over 50% from the rent and saved the business money by building two kitchens by myself.

Camp counsellor/ Lifeguard, 06/2019 – 08/2019 Camp America/ Kennolyn Camps, Soquel California

- International experience working as a camp counsellor in America through Camp America.
- My roles were: Counsellor, lifeguard, guitar instructor, and basketball coach.
- Worked as a professionally qualified RLSS UK lifeguard.
- Participated in meetings to coordinate with other staff on the camper's progress, issues, and goal achievements.
- Implemented camp activities fostering physical, social, and emotional growth.

Night shop assistant, 05/2022 – 09/2022 Nachtwinkel Lochristi Lo-Bravo, Belgium, Lochristi

- International experience in Belgium dealing with customers and fostering positive customer relationships.
- Prepared invoices for customers with large and special orders.

- 1 Bushey Road, London UB3
 4AS
- 07944588500
- alizahid98@live.co.uk
- https://alizahid117.github.io./

SKILLS

- JavaScript
- HTML, CSS
- Git
- GitHub
- Problem-solving
- Leadership and management skills
- Business administration and commercial awareness
- Revenue growth and brand management

EDUCATION

A-Levels, Biology, History, 09/2015 - 07/2017

Harlington School - London

- Biology C
- History C

GCSEs, 09/2012 - 07/2014 Harlington School - London

- 1 A (Biology A)
- 8 B's (Math's B, English B)

HOBBIES

- Guitar
- Programming
- Swimming